just out of embarrassment,
por vergüenza,
so, well, I designed the no-spill cup. It works just purely on its form. The curve on top deflects the liquid back inside every time they have tremors, and this keeps the liquid inside compared to a normal cup. But the key here is that it is not tagged as a Parkinson's patient product. It looks like a cup that could be used by you, me, any clumsy person, and that makes it much more comforting for them to use, to blend in. So, well, one problem solved, many more to go. All this while, I was interviewing him, questioning him, and then I realized that I was getting very superficial information, or just answers to my questions. But I really needed to dig deeper to get a new perspective.
por eso, bueno, diseñé la taza antiderrame. Funciona gracias a su forma. La curva superior desvía el líquido hacia adentro en cada temblor, y eso mantiene el líquido dentro en contraste con una taza normal. Lo importante aquí es que no es solo un producto para pacientes de Parkinson. Parece una taza para ser usada por Uds., o yo, o cualquier persona torpe, y eso la hace más cómoda de usar, y pasar desapercibida. Bueno, un problema resuelto, y mucho más por delante. En todo este tiempo, lo entrevisté, le pregunté, y me di cuenta de que obtenía información muy superficial, o solo respuestas a mis preguntas. Pero tenía que profundizar para obtener una nueva perspectiva.
So I thought, well, let's observe him in his daily tasks, while he's eating, while he's watching TV. And then, when I was actually observing him walking to his dining table, it struck me, this man who finds it so difficult to walk on flat land, how does he climb a staircase? Because in India we do not have a fancy rail that takes you up a staircase like in the developed countries. One actually has to climb the stairs. So he told me, "Well, let me show you how I do it." Let's take a look at what I saw. So he took really long to reach this position, and then all this while, I'm thinking, "Oh my God, is he really going to do it? Is he really, really going to do it without his walker?" And then ... (Laughter) And the turns, he took them so easily. So -- shocked? Well, I was too. So this person who could not walk on flat land was suddenly a pro at climbing stairs. On researching this, I realized that it's because it's a continuous motion. There's this other man who also suffers from the same symptoms and uses a walker,
Y pensé, bueno, observémoslo en sus tareas cotidianas, mientras come, mientras mira TV. Y al observarlo caminar hacia su mesa del comedor, me impactó que este hombre hallara dificultad al caminar en suelo plano, ¿cómo subir una escalera? Porque en India no tenemos carriles estupendos para subir escaleras como en los países desarrollados. Uno tiene que subir las escaleras. Así que me dijo: "Bueno, te mostraré cómo lo hago". Veamos lo que yo vi. Demoró mucho en llegar a esta posición, y en todo este tiempo, pienso, "Dios mío, ¿realmente lo va a hacer? ¿Realmente lo va a hacer sin andador?" Y luego... (Risas) Dio giros con mucha facilidad. ¿Impactados? Bueno, yo también. Esta persona que no podía caminar en suelo plano de repente era un profesional subiendo escaleras. Investigando, me di cuenta de que se debe a que es un movimiento continuo. Este otro hombre tiene los mismos síntomas y usa un andador,
but the moment he's put on a cycle, all his symptoms vanish, because it is a continuous motion. So the key for me was to translate this feeling of walking on a staircase back to flat land. And a lot of ideas were tested and tried on him, but the one that finally worked was this one. Let's take a look. (Laughter) (Applause)
pero cuando está en una bicicleta, desaparecen sus síntomas, porque es un movimiento continuo. La clave para mí fue traducir esta sensación de caminar escaleras al suelo plano. En él, probamos muchas ideas, pero la que finalmente funcionó fue esta. Veamos. (Risas) (Aplausos)
He walked faster, right? I call this the staircase illusion, and actually when the staircase illusion abruptly ended, he froze, and this is called freezing of gait. So it happens a lot, so why not have a staircase illusion flowing through all their rooms, making them feel much more confident? You know, technology is not always it. What we need are human-centered solutions. I could have easily made it into a projection, or a Google Glass, or something like that. But I stuck to simple print on the floor. This print could be taken into hospitals to make them feel much more welcome. What I wish to do is make every Parkinson's patient feel like my uncle felt that day. He told me that I made him feel like his old self again. "Smart" in today's world has become synonymous to high tech, and the world is only getting smarter and smarter day by day. But why can't smart be something that's simple and yet effective? All we need is a little bit of empathy and some curiosity, to go out there, observe. But let's not stop at that. Let's find these complex problems. Don't be scared of them. Break them, boil them down into much smaller problems, and then find simple solutions for them. Test these solutions, fail if needed, but with newer insights to make it better. Imagine what we all could do if we all came up with simple solutions. What would the world be like if we combined all our simple solutions? Let's make a smarter world, but with simplicity. Thank you. (Applause)
Caminó más deprisa, ¿no? Yo lo llamo la ilusión de la escalera, y en realidad cuando acabó la ilusión de la escalera abruptamente, se congeló, y esto se llama bloqueo de la marcha. Sucede mucho, de modo que ¿por qué no tener una ilusión de escalera en cada habitación, para brindar mucha más confianza? La tecnología no siempre lo es todo. Necesitamos soluciones centradas en la persona. Yo podía haber hecho una proyección o usar Google Glass, o algo así. Pero estaba limitada a impresiones en el piso. Esta impresión podría llevarse a hospitales para hacerlos sentir mucho más bienvenidos. Deseo que cada paciente de Parkinson se sienta como mi tío aquel día. Él me dijo que le hice sentir que recuperaba su viejo yo otra vez. "Smart" en el mundo actual es sinónimo de última tecnología, y el mundo se vuelve cada vez más "smart". Pero ¿por qué "smart" no puede ser algo simple y efectivo? Solo necesitamos un poco de empatía y un poco de curiosidad, salir y observar. Pero no paremos allí. Encontremos estos problemas complejos. No les temamos. Dividámoslos, descompongamos eso en problemas mucho más pequeños, y luego encontremos soluciones simples para ellos. Probemos estas soluciones, fallemos si es necesario, pero con ideas nuevas para hacerlo mejor. Imaginen lo que podríamos hacer si todos aportáramos soluciones simples. ¿Cómo sería el mundo si combináramos todas nuestras soluciones simples? Hagamos un mundo más inteligente, pero con simplicidad. Gracias. (Aplausos)